csuglobal.edu 2014-06-25

# Colorado State University - Global Campus :: Privacy Policy

Home > Privacy Policy 

**Commitment to Individual Privacy**

Colorado State University-Global Campus (CSU-Global) is committed to protecting the privacy and accuracy of confidential information submitted by employees, students, and visitors to our website. We do not actively share personal information gathered. However, because CSU-Global is a public institution, some information collected from our website and other sources may be subject to the Colorado Public (Open) Records Act. Thus, in some cases we may be compelled by law to release information gathered from our web servers. This may include server log information, e-mail messages sent to an individual identified on the website, and information collected from web-based forms.

**Colorado Public (Open) Records Act (C.R.S. 24-72 201 et seq.)**

It is the declared public policy of the State of Colorado that all public records shall be open for inspection by any person at reasonable times, except as otherwise provided by law. Public Records are defined by this law as all writings made or maintained by a state institution, such as CSU-Global, regardless of the format or medium of the records.

**Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. §1232g)**

CSU-Global also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which generally prohibits the release of students' education records without consent. FERPA only applies to currently enrolled students. For more information on FERPA, please refer to the University Policies and Guidelines section of the CSU-Global Academic Catalog.

**Information Collection**

It is CSU-Global's policy to collect the least amount of personally identifiable information required to fulfill its required duties and responsibilities, to complete a particular transaction, or as required by law. This policy applies to the collection of all personally identifiable information, regardless of the source or medium.

For site administration functions, information, other than personal information linked to a particular individual, is collected for analysis and statistical purposes of website navigation. This information is used to help diagnose problems, assess what information is of most interest, determine technical design specifications, identify system performance and/or problem areas, and other administration functions. You may choose whether or not to provide personal information to CSU-Global via the Internet. If you choose not to provide the personal information we request, you can still visit most of the CSU-Global website, but may not be able to access certain options, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you.

If you provide personal information through CSU-Global's website or an affiliate website, CSU-Global will contact you regarding educational opportunities. Any charges incurred by receiving these communications will be the sole responsibility of the recipient. At any time, you may choose to be removed from our contact lists by following the instructions included with the communication or by emailing us at Admissions@CSUGlobal.edu. To stop receiving text messages, respond to our text with the word STOP.

**Security**

Wherever your personal information may be held within CSU-Global or on its behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure.

**Browser Cookies**

Some of our web pages utilize "cookies." A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about website activity. Some cookies may serve to recall personal information previously indicated by a web user. Cookies created by CSU-Global websites cannot be read by a third party. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie or choose to block cookies entirely.

**Tracking Technologies**

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clock stream patterns; and dates and times that our site is accessed. Our use of tracking technologies allows us to analyze trends and statistics to improve our website and your web experience. Data used from tracking technologies is not linked to Web users' personal information.

**Third Party Services**

On CSU-Global’s behalf, third parties may provide certain services available on CSU-Global websites. CSU-Global may provide information, including personal information, collected on the web to third-party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information, and services. Service providers are also an important means by which CSU-Global maintains its website and mailing lists. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect personal information on our behalf.

**Disclaimer**

The information provided in this privacy statement should NOT be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or as warranting the security of information provided through this website.
